♪～
（ゼツ）やっと出かけるんだね。
（マダラ）いろいろと
予定の変更があったからな。
You're finally going out.
Well, there have been
a lot of changes to our plans.
（カブト）僕が面倒をかけたように
言わないでほしいね。
（ゼツ）おかげで作戦を
練り直したんだ。
I wish you wouldn't say it
like I'm to blame.
（カブト）おかげでキミたちの戦力は
増大したし→
Thanks to you,
we had to change our strategy.
攻撃のバリエーションも増しただろう？
Thanks to me,
your military strength and variations
of attack increased, didn't they?
（マダラ）俺が留守だからといって
妙な真似はするなよ。
Don't do anything strange
while I'm away.
仲間だろ？
もっと信頼してくれても
いいんじゃないか？
We're comrades.
You should trust me more.
お前は利害が一致した
協力者にすぎない。
You only look after
your own interests.
どこに行くのかも
教えてもらえないのかい？
You won't even tell me
where you're off to?
雨隠れの里だ。
雨隠れに？
The Hidden Rain Village.
忍界大戦に
直接かかわりあいもないのに→
The Hidden Rain?
They're not even directly involved
in the Great Ninja War,
今更なぜ？
so why are you going now?
お前に関係のないことだ。
It doesn't concern you.
((長門：待ってよ　弥彦！
Wait, Yahiko!
（小南）待って！
Wait!
（弥彦）俺が一番だ！
I'm first!
（弥彦）うわぁ～！
（２人）うん！
（２人）いっ！？
It's a toad, a toad!
A giant toad!
ガマだ　ガマ…　大ガマだ！
どうして
私たちのアジトの中に？
How'd it get inside our hideout?
どうしよう…。
What'll we do?
You're so noisy!
What's all this ruckus about?
（自来也）騒がしいのう。
なにを騒いでおる。
Jiraiya Sensei?
自来也先生。
どうだ？　似合っとるか？
Well? Does it look good on me?
似合うっていや　似合ってるけど。
Now that you mention it,
I guess so…
What's so funny?
(（自来也）何がおかしい！
おかしくない！))
It's not funny!
The Angelic Herald of Death
♪～
探し物？
Looking for something?
Yeah.
ああ。
Where did you put Nagato's corpse?
長門の遺体をどこへやった？
You won't find him here.
ここにはいないわ。
♪～
The Rinnegan…
輪廻眼…。
It seems you aren't going
to cooperate
and tell me where you hid Nagato.
長門の隠し場所を
素直に話す気はなさそうだな。
I knew that you would
appear before me.
あなたが
私の前に来ることはわかっていた。
I've been waiting for you.
So I could stop you.
待っていたわ
あなたをしとめるために。
Just because you used
to be a comrade
does not mean
I'll show you any mercy.
（マダラ）かつての仲間だからといって
手かげんはない。
The Akatsuki does not
put up with traitors.
Understand?
暁は裏切りを許さない。
いいな？
I have one question.
Why would such loyal members
as you both betray me?
ひとつ　問う。
なぜ　お前らほどのメンバーが
俺を裏切った？
You and Nagato both approved
of my Project Tsuki no Me.
お前も長門も　俺の月の眼計画の
賛同者だったはず。
If you lost to Naruto Uzumaki,
then it couldn't have
been helped.
うずまきナルト…　ヤツに敗れた
というなら　しかたがない。
But…Nagato sacrificed his life,
using the Rinne Rebirth Jutsu,
for Naruto's sake.
だが　長門は　ナルトのために
輪廻天生の術を使い　死んだ。
That jutsu was to be used
for my sake.
俺のために使うはずだった術を
使って…。
((ペインがやられるなんてこと
考えもしなかったぜ。
(これを　トビに伝える。　行くぞ))
I never imagined that
Pain would be defeated.
だが　ゼツも　何が長門の考えを
変えたのかまでは見ていない。
We must notify Tobi. Let's go.
But even Zetsu did not see
what made Nagato change his mind.
((俺の話を聞かせてやった。
I have told you my story.
(答えを聞こう))
Now let me hear your answer.
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
((人が本当の意味で
理解しあえる時代が来ると→
But I have faith that
there will come a time
(わしは信じとる))
when people can truly
understand one another.
((ナルト：アンタたちのことは理解した。
I get where you're coming from now.
それでも　やっぱり
お前らは許せねえ。
But I still…
やっぱり　憎い…。
can't forgive you.
なら　決着をつけると？
I still hate you.
Do you want to settle this, then?
でも…。
But…
エロ仙人は
俺のことを信じて　託してくれた。
Pervy Sage believed in me,
and left me his quest.
なら　俺は
エロ仙人の信じたことを信じてみる。
So I'm going to believe
in Pervy Sage's belief.
それが　俺の答えだ。
That's my answer.
ふざけるな！
Don't play with me!
今更　自来也の言ったことなど
信じられるか！
It's far too late for me to
believe Jiraiya's words!
本当の平和など
ありはしないのだ。
There's no such thing as true peace!
俺たちが呪われた世界に
生きているかぎり→
As long as we live in
this cursed world,
そんなもの　ありはしない！
peace is impossible!
なら…　なら
俺が　その呪いを解いてやる！
Then…
Then…I'll break that curse.
平和ってのが　あるなら
俺が　それを掴み取ってやる。
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
俺は諦めねぇ。
I'll never give up!
お前　それは…。
You…
That's…
Nagato? What's wrong?
長門…　どうしたの？
そのセリフは…。
Those…words…
そうだってばよ。
That's right.
They're taken straight from this book.
今のは全部　この本の中のセリフだ。
エロ仙人の書いた　最初の本だ。
The first novel written by Pervy Sage.
Pervy Sage was seriously trying
エロ仙人は　この本で
本気で世界を変えようとしてた。
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
to change the world with this.
At the end of this book,
he wrote about a student who helped
本の最後に
この本を書くヒントをくれた→
JIRAIYA
provide him with inspiration.
弟子のことが書いてあった。
It was you, Nagato.
アンタの名前だ　長門。
そんな…。
No…
そして　この本の主人公の名前…。
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
And…
the name of the hero
in this novel…
それが　ナルトだ！
is Naruto!
だから　俺の名前は→
My name is a precious memento
from Pervy Sage!
エロ仙人からもらった
大切な形見だ！
俺が諦めて　師匠の形見に
傷をつけるわけにはいかねえ！
I can't just give up and
stain the memento from my master!
俺は火影になる！
I will be the Hokage!
そんでもって
雨隠れも平和にしてみせる！
And I will bring peace
to the Hidden Rain!
俺を信じてくれ。
Please believe in me!
（長門）なぜだ…。
How?
お前はどうして
自分が変わらないと言いきれる？
How can you say that
you will never change?
これから　どれほどの痛みが
お前を襲うことになっても→
That you will not change,
no matter how great
the pain you face.
変わらないと…
自分を信じたままでいられるか？
Can you continue believing
in yourself?
Can you guarantee it?
そう言いきれるのか！？
Can you have such faith in yourself?!
自分自身を…　信じられるのか！？
And there's a lot of pain nesting
inside of me as well.
腹ん中にも
でっけぇ痛みを飼ってる。
There's no telling what kind
of pain will come after me.
これからだって　どんな痛みが
俺に襲いかかるか…。
でも…　だからって　自分を
信じられなくなっちまったら…。
But…
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
If I stop believing because of that…
主人公が変わっちまったら…
別の物語になっちまう。
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
If the hero should change,
it'll turn into another story.
師匠の残したもんとは
別の本になっちまう。
from the one my master left behind.
それじゃあ　ナルトじゃねえ！
Then it won't be Naruto!
俺は　師匠みてぇに本は書けねえ。
I can't write novels like
my master did.
だから…
続編は　俺自身の歩く生き様だ。
That's why the sequel has to
come from the life I live.
どんなに痛ぇことがあっても
歩いてく。
No matter how great the pain,
I'll continue walking.
(それが　ナルトだ！))
Because that's who Naruto is!
Naruto Uzumaki…
You think he's that worthy?
うずまきナルト…　ヤツにそれほどの
価値があるとでもいうのか？
He is the light.
彼は光…。
That's why we all…
だからこそ　みんな
希望の花を持てる。
can carry flowers of hope!
フッ…　俺に牙を向けるというのに
まだ　その衣を着てるとはな。
You bare your fangs at me,
暁に未練があるとみえる。
yet you still continue to
wear that cloak.
暁は弥彦の作った組織。
I see that you are still attached
to the Akatsuki.
この衣にある赤き雲は→
Yahiko founded the Akatsuki.
ここ　雨隠れに血の雨を降らせた
戦争の象徴。
The red cloud on this cloak
symbolizes the blood
that rained over
the Hidden Rain from war!
暁に　あなたが乗っかっただけだ。
この衣は私たちの正義。
あなたのものではない。
You are just riding on its coattails.
These cloaks are our legacy, not yours.
そして　輪廻眼は
雨隠れの忍　長門が開眼したもの。
Furthermore, Nagato,
a shinobi of the Hidden Rain,
やはり　あなたのものではない。
awakened the Rinnegan.
And that too, does not belong to you.
彼の眼は　この国の…　里の宝だ！
His eyes are this nation's…
this village's treasure!
フフフフ…
お前は２つ勘違いをしている。
You are mistaken on two points.
どうせ　最後だ。　教えてやる。
It's all over for you anyway,
so I will tell you.
暁を　弥彦に立ち上げるように
仕向けたのは俺だ。
I am the one who encouraged Yahiko
to establish the Akatsuki.
そして…
輪廻眼を長門に与えたのも俺だ。
And I was also the one
who gave Nagato the Rinnegan.
だから　返してもらうと
言ったほうが正しいか。
So it's only right for me
to ask for it back.
（マダラ）まあ　いい。
Well, no matter.
俺からすれば　お前は
何も知らない　ただの小娘。
As far as I'm concerned,
you're just a girl
who knows nothing.
ただ　今は
長門の輪廻眼の場所を→
Except that, right now,
you know where Nagato's Rinnegan is.
知っている小娘だが…。
お前を捕らえさえすれば
どうにでもなる。
Once I capture you,
I can do anything I want.
うちはの瞳力をナメるなよ　小娘。
Do not underestimate
the visual prowess of the Uchiha, girl!
《数で攻め　俺が実体化する隙を
逃さない気だな。
Using a manifold attack,
she intends to find a chance
to attack when I materialize.
いいだろう　何か策を練って
誘っているのは　わかる。
Fine. I know she has
some strategy to tempt me.
勝負してやろう》
I accept her challenge!
ここか？
Over here!
ぐっ…。
She mixed in Paper Bombs!
（マダラ）起爆札をまぜ込んだか。
I will take you with me
to the afterlife.
（小南）私が　あの世に連れていく。
We lost another member
in the Seventh Ward.
((第７区で　またメンバーがやられた。
That place is turning
into guerilla warzone.
（長門）あそこは
ゲリラ戦になってきてる。
We'd better deal with it now.
今のうちに
手を打っておかないと。
I'll go scout it out in the afternoon.
午後から　俺が偵察に行く。
Nagato, rest awhile.
長門　少し休め。
お前は無理をしなくていい。
Don't overdo it.
No, but…
No buts. Rest.
いや　でも…。
いいから休め。　俺が行く。
I will go.
Be careful, Yahiko.
（小南）気をつけて　弥彦。
You don't need to see me off!
See to Nagato's wound, will you?
見送りなんていい。
それより　長門の傷を診てやれ。
From now on,
save your worrying for him.
これからは
心配する気持は　アイツに注げ。
Nagato is the keystone
of the Akatsuki!
He will become the man
アイツは　暁の要。
who changes this nation
and this world!
これから
この国を　世界を変える男になる。
The same can be said of you.
Everyone respects and admires you.
それは　あなたも同じこと。
Nagato is no different.
皆　あなたという人間を慕い
ついてきている。
Nagato is going to be…
the bridge to peace.
それは　何より長門も同じ。
長門は…　アイツは
平和への架け橋になる男だ。
My job is to be a pillar
that supports that bridge.
俺の役目は
その橋を支える柱になることだ。
Yahiko.
弥彦…。
This nation continues to weep.
It continues to endure pain.
この国は　相変わらず泣いている。
I used to hate this land
that cries all the time.
痛みに耐え続けている。
But now, I want to save it.
昔は　泣いてばかりの
この国が嫌いだった。
It's what I want with all my heart.
だが　今は救ってやりたい。
It reminds me of the crybaby
that I used to be
心から　そう思ってんだ。
and I can't ignore it.
フッ…　泣き虫だった俺と似てて→
Yahiko!
ほっとけなくてな。
Be careful.
弥彦…。
He is the bridge to peace.
His will itself is the bridge.
気をつけて。
（長門）平和の架け橋は　彼だよ。
Nagato…
We believe in Yahiko!
彼の意志そのものがね。
Let's go, everyone!
（小南）長門…。
Right!
俺たちは　弥彦を信じる。
I will be a pillar that supports
two bridges: Yahiko and Nagato!
行くぞ　みんな。
(はい))
《小南：私は…　弥彦と長門→
２つの架け橋を支える柱になる》
甘く見ていたな。
考えれば　元　暁メンバーだ…　お前も。
I didn't take you seriously enough.
ハア…　ハア…　ハア…。
I should have remembered that
you are a former member
of the Akatsuki…
吸い込む瞬間に自爆して俺ごと
やるつもりだったようだな。
The moment I sucked you in,
だが失敗だ。
you intended to blow yourself up,
and take me with you.
爆発ごと吸い込んだ。
俺のほうが速かった。
However, you failed.
I sucked in the explosion itself.
少し食らったが。
I was faster, although I felt
a little of the impact.
おかげで　お前も助かったな。
感謝しろ。
And luckily, you were spared too.
これで　お前の秘策も終わりか？
You should be grateful.
Does this mean
your secret strategy is over?
マダラ　あなたにひとつ問う。
Madara, let me ask you one thing.
何だ？
なぜ　あなたは私たちに
裏切られたか　わかる？
What is it?
Do you know why we betrayed you?
なぜナルトを信じたか　わかる？
Do you know why
we have faith in Naruto?
さぁな　それはお前らの問題だ。
Well now… That's your problem.
しかも　ナルトは　青臭い理想を
追いかけるだけの小僧。
Besides, Naruto is just
a naïve child
本当の平和だ希望だと
長門が情に流されたとしても→
chasing after an immature dream.
I can see if Nagato was swayed
by the thought of true peace
and hope.
小南　お前まで。
ナルトに会って気づかされた。
((ソイツも連れて帰んのか？
ええ。　このペイン天道こそ→
弥彦の亡骸で作ったもの。
私たちにとっては大切な人。
弥彦ってソイツだったのか。
お前はどうするんだ？
もう暁に戻るとは
思いたかねえけど。
暁は抜ける。
私にとっては
弥彦と長門がすべてだった。
弥彦の夢。　そして長門の夢。
２人の夢がお前に託されたなら→
これからは　お前が２人の夢だ。
長門がお前を信じたなら
私はお前を信じる。
私たち雨隠れは　お前とともに→
２人の夢を
追いかけることにしよう。
ナルトって名前と　諦めないド根性。
それから痛み。
それが　師匠と兄弟子から
譲り受けたもんだ。
(今度こそ　お前は散ることのない
希望の花であってくれ))
あなたは闇。
光のない世界では
花は枯れるしかない！
エヘヘヘッ。　リーリーリーリー。
《サスケ：野郎　調子にのりやがって》
《ぜってぇ　盗塁　決めてやる》
リーリー。
（リー）お呼びですか　ナルト君！
オメエを呼んだんじゃねえ！
（カカシ）アウト！
え～っ！
僕は　何か→
悪いことをしたのでしょうか。
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。